bankserv.co.za 2015-03-21

# Privacy » BankservAfrica

BankservAfrica is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This statement of privacy applies to the BankservAfrica website and governs data collection and usage. By using the BankservAfrica website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## Collection of your personal information

BankservAfrica collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. BankservAfrica also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your postal code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favourites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by BankservAfrica. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by BankservAfrica for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the BankservAfrica website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through BankservAfrica’s public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: BankservAfrica does not read any of your private online communications.

BankservAfrica encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from BankservAfrica so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. BankservAfrica is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the BankservAfrica and BankservAfrica family of websites.

## Use of your personal information

BankservAfrica collects and uses your personal information to operate the BankservAfrica website and deliver the services you have requested. BankservAfrica also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from BankservAfrica and its affiliates. BankservAfrica may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

BankservAfrica does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. BankservAfrica may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, BankservAfrica may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to BankservAfrica, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

BankservAfrica does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

BankservAfrica keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within BankservAfrica, in order to determine what BankservAfrica services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customised content and advertising within BankservAfrica to customers whose behaviour indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

BankservAfrica websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on BankservAfrica or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of BankservAfrica; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of BankservAfrica, or the public.

## Use of cookies

The BankservAfrica website use "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a webpage server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the webserver that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalise BankservAfrica pages, or register with the BankservAfrica site or services, a cookie helps BankservAfrica to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same BankservAfrica website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the BankservAfrica features that you customised.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the BankservAfrica services or Web sites you visit.

## Security of your personal information

BankservAfrica secures your personal information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. BankservAfrica secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## Changes to this statement

BankservAfrica will occasionally update this statement of privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. BankservAfrica encourages you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how BankservAfrica is protecting your information.

## Contact information

BankservAfrica welcomes your comments regarding this statement of privacy. If you believe that BankservAfrica has not adhered to this statement, please contact BankservAfrica at [info@bankservafrica.com](mailto:info@bankservafrica.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
